{
  "javaquestions": [
      {
      "id" : 0,
      "questionType" : "",
      "questionText" : "",
      "correctAnswer" : "",
      "options" : ["", ""]
      },
     {
      "id" : 1,
      "questionType" : "true_false",
      "questionText" : "In an instance method or a constructor, 'this' is a reference to the current object.",
      "correctAnswer" : "true",
      "explanation" : "This referrs to a current object.",
      "options" : ["true", "false"]
      },
     {
      "id": 2,
      "questionType" : "text_input",
      "questionText" : "Typical uses of a ___ variable are to accumulate a total.",
      "correctAnswer" : "static",
      "explanation" : "Static variables can be used to accumulate a total",
      "answerFieldId" : "answer_to_question"
      },
     {
      "id" : 3,
      "questionType" : "true_false",
      "questionText" : "Does void have a return type?",
      "correctAnswer" : "false",
      "explanation" : "Void does not return anything.",
      "options" : ["true", "false"]
      },
     {
      "id" : 4,
      "questionType" : "true_false",
      "questionText" : "An uninitialized object variable is called a null reference or null pointer.",
      "correctAnswer" : "true",
      "explanation" : "If it is uninitialized, it has no value, returning null.",
      "options" : ["true", "false"]
      },
     {
      "id" : 5,
      "questionType" : "mc",
      "questionText" : "What does this return: int x=2; System.out.println(x+'1');",
      "correctAnswer" : "21",
      "explanation" : "X is an integer and 1 is a string. When they are combined they are manually put together",
      "options" : ["3", "21", "2"]
      },
      {
      "id" : 6,
      "questionType" : "text_input",
      "questionText" : "The words inside the parenthesis in a function are called p_____.",
      "correctAnswer" : "parameters",
      "explanation" : "Parameters are used in parenthesis in a function .",
      "answerFieldId" : "answer_to_question"
      },
      {
      "id" : 7,
      "questionType" : "true_false",
      "questionText" : "Constructor overloading is not possible in Java.",
      "correctAnswer" : "false",
      "explanation" : "Constructor overloading is possible in Java. The Java compiler differentiates the constructors based on the number and the type of the arguments.",
      "options" : ["true", "false"]
      },
      {
      "id" : 8,
      "questionType" : "text_input",
      "questionText" : "Assignment operator is evaluated ___ to right.",
      "correctAnswer" : "left",
      "explanation" : "Assignment operator is evaluated left to right.",
      "answerFieldId" : "answer_to_question"
      },
      {
      "id" : 9,
      "questionType" : "mc",
      "questionText" : "If System.out.println(x+'5') prints out 55, then the data type of X must be a(n)",
      "correctAnswer" : "integer",
      "explanation" : "5 is a string so X must be a number, and there are no decimals so it is an integer.",
      "options" : ["boolean", "double", "integer"]
      },
      {
      "id" : 10,
      "questionType" : "mc",
      "questionText" : "What type of language is Java?  ",
      "correctAnswer" : "interpreted",
      "explanation" : "Java is an interpreted language.",
      "options" : ["compiled", "interpreted","both"]
      },
      {
      "id" : 11,
      "questionType" : "text_input",
      "questionText" : "Out of int,double, and string, which of the following is not a primitive data type in Java?",
      "correctAnswer" : "string",
      "explanation" : "String is not a primitive data type in Java.",
      "answerFieldId" : "answer_to_question"
      },
      {
      "id" : 12,
      "questionType" : "text_input",
      "questionText" : "What is the output of System.out.println('Hello ' + 5)",
      "correctAnswer" : "Hello 5",
      "explanation" : "It prints the string with the number attached.",
      "answerFieldId" : "answer_to_question"
      },
      {
      "id" : 13,
      "questionType" : "text_input",
      "questionText" : "What is the output of the following code: System.out.println(5 == 5.0);",
      "correctAnswer" : "true",
      "explanation" : "In Java, the '==' operator checks if two values are equal, regardless of their data type. Therefore, 5 and 5.0 are considered equal.",
      "answerFieldId" : "answer_to_question"
      },
      {
      "id" : 14,
      "questionType" : "mc",
      "questionText" : "Which data type is a decimal value?",
      "correctAnswer" : "double",
      "explanation" : "A double lets you write a decimal value;",
      "options" : ["string", "double", "integer"]
      },
      {
      "id" : 15,
      "questionType" : "mc",
      "questionText" : "Which keyword is used to create a subclass in Java?",
      "correctAnswer" : "extends",
      "explanation" : "The 'extends' keyword is used to create a subclass in Java.",
      "options" : ["this", "extends","super"]
      },
      {
      "id" : 16,
      "questionType" : "true_false",
      "questionText" : "What is the output of the following code: System.out.println(10 > 5 && 5 < 3);",
      "correctAnswer" : "false",
      "explanation" : "The '&&' operator in Java is the logical AND operator. It returns true if both operands are true. In this case, 10 > 5 is true, but 5 < 3 is false, so the overall expression is false.",
      "options" : ["true", "false"]
      
      },
      {
      "id" : 17,
      "questionType" : "text_input",
      "questionText" : "What is the access modifier used for a private method in Java?",
      "correctAnswer" : "private",
      "explanation" : "The 'private' access modifier is used to indicate that a method can only be accessed within the same class.",
       "answerFieldId" : "answer_to_question"
      
      },
      {
      "id" : 18,
      "questionType" : "true_false",
      "questionText" : "Java files end with the extension .js",
      "correctAnswer" : "false",
      "explanation" : ".js is used for JavaScript. Java files use .java",
      "options" : ["true", "false"]
      },
      {
      "id" : 19,
      "questionType" : "mc",
      "questionText" : "Which of the following is a method of the String class in Java?",
      "correctAnswer" : "length()",
      "explanation" : "The 'length()' method returns the length of a string in Java.",
      "options" : ["length()", "count()","size()"]
      },
      {
      "id" : 20,
      "questionType" : "mc",
      "questionText" : "Can a boolean operator return true or false?",
      "correctAnswer" : "both",
      "explanation" : "Boolean check if something is true or false.",
      "options" : ["only true", "only false", "both"]
      }
  ]
}